通关《我的世界》，还得恪守伊斯兰教的清规戒律，这事儿能成吗？
Can you beat Minecraft without breaking any of the rules of Islam?
本视频仅供娱乐，无对宗教及相关人士的诋毁，同时亦无宣传之意味，请审核放行
在咱揭晓答案之前，有几件事得先说道说道
Before we answer this question, we have to establish a couple of things.
首先，伊斯兰教的规矩是啥
First, what are the rules of Islam?
其次，哪些规矩在《我的世界》里也得算数
And second, which ones actually apply to Minecraft?
据我一番考究，伊斯兰教里能做和不能做的事，主要源自两大宝典
From my research, the rules of what you can and cannot do in Islam come from two main sources.
一个是源自伊斯兰圣典《古兰经》的教法，另一个则是伊斯兰的五功
The Sharia law, which comes from the holy text of Islam, the Quran, and the five pillars of Islam.
这五功可谓信仰的基石，所以咱们在游戏里也得一丝不苟地遵从
The five pillars are the foundation of the faith, so we need to make sure we follow these in Minecraft.
这五功分别是：证言（念）、礼拜（礼）、天课（课）
The pillars are Shahada, the declaration of faith, Salah, the daily prayer, Zakat, charitable giving,
斋戒（斋），以及朝觐（朝）
Psalm, fasting during the month of Ramadan, and Hajj, the pilgrimage to Mecca.
这五条里头，真正能在游戏里身体力行的，其实也就三条
Of these five, there are really only three that we can follow and obey in Minecraft.
咱先从最简单的“证言”开始
Let's start with the easiest one, Shahada, the declaration of faith.
为了完成这一功，伊斯兰的信徒们需要念诵这么一句话
In order to fulfill this pillar, followers of Islam are expected to utter this phrase,
万物非主，唯有真主，穆罕默德是真主的使者
There is no God but Allah, and Muhammad is Allah's prophet.
那么，这就开个新世界，在聊天框里敲下这行字，为咱们的征途拉开序幕
So let's start up a new world and type these words in the chat to start off our run.
好了，搞定
Okay, boom.
我已宣示信仰，五功之一顺利达成
I've declared my faith and checked off one of the pillars.
我知道这第一条规矩简单得很，但您别急，大的还在后头呢
I know that first rule was easy, but just wait a little bit and see what else is in store for me.
先去砍点木头，如何
Let's get some wood, shall we?
咱有八块木头了
We have eight wood.
好嘞，这就扔掉四块
Okay, we just threw out four.
等等，为啥要把一半的木头给扔了？
Okay, wait a second. Why would we throw out half of our wood?
那我给各位隆重介绍一下，咱们必须遵守的第二功：天课，也就是乐善好施
Let me introduce you to the second pillar that we have to follow, zakat, or charitable giving.
在现实世界里，遵循这条教义的穆斯林会把自己收入的一部分捐给慈善事业
In the real world, Muslims who follow this pillar donate a fraction of their money to charity.
而在《我的世界》里，既然钱这玩意儿不太好使
In Minecraft, since money is kind of non-existent,
我就规定，我获取的所有资源都得捐出一半
I'm going to say that we will have to donate half of all the resources that I obtained.
所以要是我拿到两根烈焰棒，就得捐一根
So if I get two blaze rods, I have to donate one.
要是挖到二十颗钻石，就得捐十颗，以此类推
If I get 20 diamonds, I have to donate 10, and so on.
我知道这比现实中穆斯林的做法要严苛
I know that this is harder than what Muslims do in real life,
但咱玩的就是个挑战嘛，我觉得这样会很有趣
but I want this to be a challenge, so I think this will be pretty fun.
好，一旦咱把这些原木捐出去，剩下的木头想怎么用就怎么用
Okay, so like once we've donated these logs, we can use however much of the wood we want in whatever way we want.
我们只需捐出最基础的资源量就行
We just have to donate like the base amount of resources.
好，再来挖点石头
Okay, let's grab some stone.
然后照例扔掉一半
And we gotta throw half of it out.
行，来做点工具
Okay, let's make some tools.
好了，现在咱也算有点家当了
Okay, now that we have a little bit of stuff,
赶紧多囤点木头，这样以后就不用为这事儿发愁了
let's grab like a bunch of wood so that we don't have to worry about that for the rest of the time.
嗯，我看是够了
Okay, I think that's enough.
哦，看那有只鸡，宰了它
Ooh, look a chicken. We can kill this thing.
且慢，未来的我
Not so fast, me!
现在正是引出本次挑战第三条规矩的绝佳时机，我管它叫“清真法则”
This is a good time to introduce you to the third rule of the challenge. I'll be calling it the Halal Rule.
清真法则嘛，顾名思义
The Halal Rule is exactly what it sounds like.
我必须采用清真方式屠宰动物
I will have to be killing animals using the Halal Method,
这种方式强调动物必须是活蹦乱跳且健康的
which stresses the importance of a living and healthy animal,
屠宰时要用锋利的刀具，并在动手的那一刻呼唤安拉之名
a sharp knife for the incision, and invoking the name of Allah at the point of the kill.
所以，咱们在游戏里的准则就是，动物必须是成年体
So, our guidelines in Minecraft were that it has to be a fully grown animal.
我们必须用剑或者斧子一击毙命
We have to one-shot it with either a sword or an axe.
且每次动手前，都必须在聊天框里输入“奉至仁至慈的安拉之名，安拉至大”
And we have to type bismala Allahu Akbar in the chat every single time before we kill an animal.
哦对了，咱还不能吃猪肉，也不能杀猪
Oh, yeah. Also, we can't eat or kill pigs.
好了，我的首次清真屠宰要开始了，先在聊天框里打好字
Alright, here goes my first Halal Kill. Just gotta type it in the chat.
而且必须一击毙命，要是没能一招秒了，挑战就当场失败
And we have to one-shot. If we don't one-shot, then we instantly lose the challenge.
好，好，成功了
Okay, okay, we did it.
嘿，这儿还有一只鸡
Okay, here's another chicken.
记住，这些规矩是会叠加的，所以我杀掉的动物也得捐出一半
Okay, now keep in mind, these rules stack, so I'll have to donate half of all the animals I kill.
这么一来，搞点吃的都会变成一件苦差事
So, getting food is gonna be a huge pain.
你嘛，我们可不能吃
We can't eat you.
喔，这个洞穴看起来不错
Ooh, this looks like a good cave.
好了，我们挖了8个铁和12个煤，但这意味着我们实际只拥有4个铁和6个煤
Okay, we got 8 iron and 12 coal, which really means we got 4 iron and 6 coal.
我真是恨透了捐东西这个设定
I actually hate just donating stuff.
我恨啊，我恨死捐东西了（奸笑）
I hate it. I hate donating stuff.
好，我们有4个铁，足够做一面盾牌和一个桶
Okay, so we have 4 iron. That's enough for a shield and a bucket.
这个桶我们稍后有大用
We're gonna need this bucket for later, and
而用它要做的事，恐怕是我在《我的世界》里干过的最烦人的事之一了
what we're gonna do with the bucket is probably one of the most annoying things I've ever had to do in Minecraft.
好了，我们得杀几只羊来做张床
Alright, we need to kill some sheep for a bed.
哦，这儿就有几只羊
Oh, here's some sheep right here.
喔，是只小白
Ooh, it's a skeleton.
希望它没瞧见我
I hope it doesn't see me.
等等
Okay, wait a second.
我干嘛要怕区区一只小白呢？
Why am I scared of fighting one skeleton?
那就让我再给各位介绍几条挑战规则，这几条都来自伊斯兰教法
Well, let me introduce you to a couple more rules of the challenge, both coming from the Sharia law.
第一条，严禁谋杀
The first is, no murder allowed.
让我给你们念一段《古兰经》里关于这个话题的引文
Let me read you a quote from the Quran about this topic.
“他们只祈祷真主，不祈祷别的神灵
And they do not call upon another god with Allah, and do not slay the soul,
他们不违背真主的禁令而杀人， 除非由于偿命”
which Allah has forbidden, except in the requirements of justice.
我希望各位注意最后那部分
I want you to pay attention to that last part.
“除非由于偿命”
Except in the requirements of justice.
换句话说，如果一个怪物需要被绳之以法，那我们就可以动手
In other words, if a mob needs to be brought to justice, then we can kill them.
所以正式的挑战规则是，除非怪物先企图攻击我们，否则我们不能主动杀生
So the official challenge rule is we cannot kill a mob unless they have attempted to hit us first,
这样才符合“非因正义不得杀戮”的条款
thus fulfilling the clause of not murdering unless it is in the name of justice.
但先别急，关于打怪我们还有另一条规矩
But hold your horses, we have another rule about fighting mobs.
让我再带你们回到《古兰经》，看看关于临阵脱逃是怎么说的
Let me take you back to the Quran with a quote about fleeing from a battle.
在那日，谁以背向敌，谁要受真主的谴怒
If any do turn his back to them on such a day, unless it be in a stratagem of war,
他们的归宿是火狱，那归宿真恶劣
or to retreat to a troop of his own, he draws on himself the wrath of Allah, and his abode in hell, an evil refugee indeed.
这意味着一旦战斗打响，我们就不能逃跑，否则挑战自动失败
This means we cannot run away from a fight once it is started, or else we automatically lose the challenge.
所以，如果你还没搞明白的话，那就是我们必须先让怪物打到我们
So if you're still confused, we have to let mobs hit us before we hit them,
才能还手，而且一旦被打，就不能逃跑，直到把它们干掉为止
and we also cannot run away from them once we're hit, until they're dead.
好了，要是你从这场战斗中溜了，那就全完了，游戏结束
Okay, so if you've run away from this battle, it's over. It's done.
来吧蜘蛛，它想打我，所以我可以还手了
Okay, come here spider. He attempted to hit me so I can hit him.
现在我只需要足够的羊毛来做张床
Now all I need is enough wool to make a bed.
来吧僵尸，打我一下我好宰了你
Come here zombie, hit me so I can kill you.
好了，让我们捐掉一半的羊毛、一半的羊肉
Okay, so let's donate half of this wool, half of this mutton,
一半的这个、一半的那个，这些都没法用
half of this, half of that, half of that, can't use any of that.
现在，真正的挑战要在我们睡一觉后才开始
Now, the challenge really starts after we go to sleep.
一旦我们醒来，整个挑战中最艰难、最烦人的一条规则就将生效
So once we wake up, the hardest and most annoying rule of the whole challenge is going to start taking effect.
是时候履行伊斯兰教的最后一功了
It's time for the last pillar of Islam that we need to follow.
礼拜，也就是每日的祷告
Salah, or the daily prayer.
穆斯林们相信每日要祷告五次，分别在黎明、正午、下午、日落和夜晚
Muslims believe in prayer five times a day, one at dawn, midday, afternoon, sunset, and night.
所以我们也要在《我的世界》里做完全相同的事情
So we're going to be doing the exact same thing within Minecraft.
鉴于《我的世界》里一天只有十分钟
Since Minecraft days are ten minutes long,
我们可以给祷告设个计时器，确保每天都能在精准的时间进行
we can put a timer on our prayers to make sure we do it at the exact right time every day.
穆斯林们平时的祷告方式相当复杂
Muslims have a complicated way that they pray normally.
但在这个挑战中，我们得用那桶水给自己净身三次，以模仿“小净”的仪式
But for this challenge, we'll have to rinse ourselves three times with the water bucket, mimicking the Wudu practice.
然后，我们面朝北方蹲伏十秒钟，以模仿朝向麦加祷告的习俗
Then, we will crouch facing north for ten seconds, mimicking the practice of praying towards Mecca.
所以无论我们身处何种险境，无论离死亡有多近
So no matter what situation we're in, no matter how close we are to dying,
只要计时器归零，我们就必须面朝北方、净身三次、然后蹲伏十秒
if that timer hits zero, we have to face north, rinse ourselves three times, and crouch for ten seconds.
雷打不动
No matter what.
好了，让我找找北边……
Alright, so let me find the north facing...
好，这边是北
Okay, this is north.
开始
Okay.
四、五、六、七、八、九、十
Four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
好了，第一次祷告完成
Okay, there's our first prayer.
搞定
Done.
我要不要干掉这只末影人
Should I kill this Enderman?
我觉得应该试试，毕竟我需要一大堆珍珠，对吧
I think I should try, because I'm going to need a bunch of pearls, right?
好，我们得先让它打一下
Okay, so we have to let him hit us.
好，所以……
Okay, so...
好，它打我了
Okay, he hit us.
酷
Okay, cool.
这样就一颗珍珠到手了
So that's one pearl.
这事儿可不轻松
This is not going to be easy.
好，我现在想去矿洞里转转，看能不能挖到点钻石
Okay, what I want to do now is hit the caves and see if we can get some diamonds.
好，我能来个信仰之跃落地水吗
Okay, can I hit this MLG water bucket?
简单
Easy.
手拿把掐
Too easy.
等等，又快到祷告时间了
Wait, it's almost time to pray again.
我的天哪
Oh my gosh.
老兄，这怪物也太多了
Dude, there's so many mobs.
真的好多
Actually, so many.
老兄，还有五秒就得祷告了
Dude, it's time to pray in like five seconds.
好，面朝北
Okay, face north.
净身三次
Three rinses.
现在开始十秒
Now ten seconds.
我刚才差点就因为忘了祷告而挑战失败了
I almost just lost the challenge because I didn't pray.
太刺激了
That's crazy.
哦
Oh.
我好想逃，却逃不掉~
I would run, but I can't.
我死定了
I'm totally gonna die.
我觉得现在是时候提一件事了
I think now would be a good time to mention something.
尽管我没开极限模式，但如果我死了，我还是会算作挑战失败
Even though I'm not on hardcore, if I die, I'm still counting that as a loss.
我不开极限模式的唯一原因，是穆斯林相信有来生
The only reason I'm not on hardcore is because Muslims believe in life after death.
所以是的，如果我死了，我就得从头再来
So yeah, if I die, I gotta start all over.
另外，我开世界的时候也忘了选极限模式
Also, I forgot to put it in hardcore whenever I started the world.
这下不妙了
This is not good.
我得确保这些家伙每个都先打到我，然后我才能动手
I gotta make sure each one of these dudes hit me before I can kill them.
好
A-ha.
信不信由你，又快到下一次祷告时间了
Okay, believe it or not, it's almost time for the next prayer.
所以……
So...
这真的太烦人了
This is actually so annoying.
我就得停下手里所有的事情
Like, I literally just have to stop everything I'm doing.
我必须时刻盯着时钟
I have to always watch the clock.
祷告之间差不多就隔了两分半钟
It's literally like two and a half minutes apart from each other.
而且我还得捐掉我所有东西的一半
And the fact that I have to donate all my stuff, like half of it.
这真的烦透了
It's actually so annoying.
好了，我正式断粮了
Okay, I'm officially out of food.
好，祷告时间到
Okay, it's time to pray.
一、二、三……九、十
One, two, three, nine, ten.
行，看来我们最好还是去挖点钻石
Okay, I guess we better just try and get some diamonds.
在我挖钻石的时候，我只想重申一下，同时记着这么多规则压力有多大
While I'm grabbing these diamonds, I just want to reiterate how stressful it is to be keeping track of all these rules.
我不但得盯着时钟，规划好自己的行动，免得在祷告时送命
Not only do I have to keep my eye on the clock and plan out what I want to do so that I don't die praying,
我还有一大堆其他事儿得操心
I have a bunch of other stuff I gotta worry about too.
我的意思是，我们现在已经有大概六条规则了
I mean, we're already up to like six rules.
而且相信我，后头还有更多呢
And trust me, there's more where that came from.
好了，我急需食物
Okay, I really need some food.
趁现在，我们把所有收获的一半都捐出去
While we're here, let's donate half of everything we got.
噢，心在滴血
Oh, that hurts.
十七颗钻石就这么捐给慈善了
Seventeen diamonds donated to charity.
好了，我们快要凑齐全套钻甲了
Okay, we're almost at full diamond.
对于第一天来说，这已经相当不错了
That's pretty good for like day one.
喔，一个废弃传送门
Ooh, a ruined portal.
看看这箱子里有啥
Let's see what's in this chest.
且慢，且慢
Up, up, up.
小心点，伙计
Be careful, man.
偷盗的男女，你们当割去他们俩的手
As to the thief, male or female, cut off his or her hands.
以报他们俩的罪行，以示真主的惩戒
A punishment by way of example from Allah for their pride.
所以，是的，我们不能从任何建筑里搜刮任何东西
So yeah, we're not allowed to loot anything from any structures.
无论是村庄、废弃传送门还是别的什么
Not villages, not ruined portals, not anything.
我们什么都不能拿
We're not allowed to take anything.
除非我们想让自己的手被剁掉
Unless we want to get our hands chopped off.
锋利五
Sharpness five!
我的天，在最无力的时候遇上了最想要的人
Oh my gosh, why do the chest look like that whenever I can't get stuff?
好了伙计，我们再去挖点钻石
Alright man, let's get some more of these diamonds.
我的天，我刚才差点就一命呜呼了
Oh my gosh, I almost just died.
三、四、五
Three, four, five.
好，我们现在全套钻石套了
Okay, we are now full diamond.
我看是时候去下界了
I think it's time to go to the nether.
哦，熔岩湖，太好了
Ooh, lava pool, yes.
老兄，还有更多钻石
Bro, more diamonds.
钻石
DIAMOND!
老兄，这可能是我在所有世界里遇到过的最逆天的钻石运气了
Dude, this might be like the craziest diamond luck I've ever had on any world.
好了，看看这个出生点怎么样
Alright, let's see if this spawn is any good.
在我们去下界之前，让我先解释一下我们将在这里面临的几个难题
Before we go to the nether, let me explain a couple of things that will be difficult for us in here.
首先是祷告
First of all, the prey.
既然我们祷告前必须用水净身三次，那在下界里该怎么办呢
Since we have to rinse ourselves off three times with water before we pray, how are we going to do this in the nether?
这个嘛，我们将用炼药锅来装水
Well, we're going to use a cauldron to house the water.
我们得把它放下来，装上水，然后跳进去再出来三次，这样祷告才算数
We'll have to place it down, place the water, then jump in and out of it three times in order for the prayer to count.
另一个问题是，我们至少要搞到12根烈焰棒，因为有一半都得上交
The other thing is that we have to get at least 12 blaze rods, cause we'll have to be donating half of them.
再次提醒，在下界里，我们每个游戏日要祷告五次
So just as a reminder, while in the nether, we'll have to pray five times per Minecraft day.
我们得捐出一半的资源
We'll have to donate half of all the resources.
我们必须先让每个要杀的怪物打一下，并且不能从任何战斗中撤退
We have to let each mob we kill hit us first, and we won't be able to retreat from any battle we get into.
简单，对吧
Simple, right?
我的天，老兄你看，那儿就是个要塞，太棒了
Oh my gosh, dude, look, it's a fortress right there. Yes, okay.
老兄，这运气简直逆天，一、二、三……九、十
Dude, this is actually so lucky. One, two, three, nine, ten.
好，看来……这个方法可行
Okay, so that's... that method will work.
好了，我们现在直到明天早上都不用再祷告了
Okay, so we don't have to pray until tomorrow morning now.
所以我们还有……大概七分半钟的时间
So we have a little... we have like seven and a half minutes.
好，我得让这只烈焰人打我，来啊，打我
Okay, I need this blaze to hit me. Come on, hit me.
好，来了，过来吧你
Okay, yep. Come here, buster.
我的天，上来就一根棒子，来啊，打我，打我，打我
Oh my gosh, already one rod. Come on, hit me. Hit me. Hit me.
我的……老兄，我简直是Dream附体，好了，我得省着点吃
Oh my... dude, I'm actually Dream. Okay, I have to be really conservative with food.
好了，我们还有大约六分半钟就要下次祷告了
Okay, we have about six and a half minutes until the next prayer.
哦，来啊，打我，打我，打我，打我
Oh! Come on, hit me. Hit me. Hit me. Hit me. Hit me.
哎呦我，这操作够不够Dream，好了，我们还有六分钟
Oh my... dude, I'm actually dream. Okay, we have six minutes.
来啊，打我，打我，打我
Come on, hit me. Hit me. Hit me.
好了，我们的食物储备情况不容乐观
Okay, we are not looking good in terms of food.
哎呦我操
Oh my gosh.
这儿也太多了，打我，打我，打我
There's so many. Hit me. Hit me. Hit me.
嘿老兄，我没吃的了，盾牌也快……我准备撤了，好，还有大概一分钟
Hey, dude, I'm out of food, and my shield is on... I'm about to head out. Okay, we got about one minute,
看来我们得跟这些家伙干一架了
and it looks like we have to fight these guys.
我要不要下去拿那个
Should I go down there and get that?
哎呦我
Oh, gosh.
差点完几把蛋了
Die.
哦，还有十秒祷告
Oh, ten seconds until the prayer.
确保我们面朝北，净身三次
Make sure we're facing north. That's ourselves three times.
二、三……九、十
Two, three, nine, ten.
是啊，要是我再卷入一场战斗，我就死定了，我得去搞点吃的
Yeah, if I get into another fight, I'm cooked. I need to go get some more food.
好了，我们回来了，干就完了
All right, we're back. Hit me, hit me, hit me, hit me, hit me.
好，理论上我们已经够了，但为了保险起见，我想再多拿一根
Okay, we theoretically have enough. I want to get one more just for safety.
刚才真是烦透了
That was so annoying.
我什么都没了，方块没了，食物没了，简直山穷水尽，一穷二白了
I'm out of literally everything. I'm out of blocks. I'm out of food. I'm out of actually just everything.
好了，既然我们出了下界，就得来谈谈挑战剩下的规则了
Okay, now that we're out of the nether, we need to discuss the remainder of the challenge rules.
没错，还不止一条，我只是塞不进这张图里了
And yes, there are more than one. I just couldn't fit it on this map thing.
第一条，禁用药水，这是因为伊斯兰教法禁止饮酒
Okay, the first, no potion. This is because of the Sharia law of no alcohol.
第二条，禁用附魔，这是因为伊斯兰教法禁止使用黑魔法
The second is no enchantments. This is because of the Sharia law for no practicing black magic.
第三条规则和末影龙有关
The third rule has to do with the ender dragon.
因为在末地，时间和太阳位置的概念都不存在
Because the concept of time and the position of the sun don't exist in the end,
所以我规定，我们不能祷告
I'm going to say that we're not allowed to pray.
这就意味着我们必须在七分三十秒的时限内击败末影龙
This will make it to where we have to beat the dragon within a time limit of 7 minutes and 30 seconds,
因为这是我们两次祷告之间的最长时间间隔
because that's the maximum amount of time between our prayers.
第四条，也是挑战的最后一条规则，是禁止繁殖、奴役或利用村民
The fourth and final rule of the challenge is no breeding, enslaving, or taking advantage of villagers.
说到村民，我原本计划是和牧师交易来搞定剩下的末影珍珠
Speaking of villagers, my plan to get the rest of the ender pearls was to trade with the cleric.
所以我找到了一个村庄，并开始实施我的计划
So I found a village and started to put my plan into motion.
好，来做个制箭台
Okay, let's make a fletching table.
这家伙可以用木棍换绿宝石，这简直完美
Okay, this dude will trade us emeralds for sticks. So that's perfect.
现在我们只要去砍一大堆木头，然后再捐掉一半
Now all we have to do is just get a bunch of wood, and then we have to donate half of it.
之后就可以和村民交易了
And then we can trade with the villagers.
要攒够买末影珍珠的绿宝石，实际上会花掉我天长地久的时间
So it's actually going to take me like forever to get enough like emeralds for ender pearls.
二、三、四、五
Two, three, four, five.
好，我早就知道因为那个捐赠规则，这事会很花时间
Okay, I knew that this would take a long time because of the whole donation thing,
但你猜猜实际花了多久
but guess how long it actually took?
一个小时，一个半小时？
One hour? An hour and a half?
足足四个小时，花了我四个小时！
Four hours. It took me four hours.
你知道那段时间里我得祷告多少次吗
Do you know how many times I had to pray during that?
好，我回去数了一下
Okay, I went back and counted.
我祷告了多少次
How many times I prayed?
一百零三次！
A hundred and three times!
哦，总算好了
Oh, finally.
好了，老兄
All right, dude.
我看我们准备好出发了
I think we're ready to go.
好，看看我们得往哪边走
All right, let's see which way we got to go.
好嘞
All right.
然后它碎了
And it breaks.
当然会碎了，老兄
Of course it does, dude.
哦，在这儿呢
Oh, here it is.
而且传送门里一个眼睛都没有
And there's no eyes in the portal.
我得一路折返回去，再搞齐一套末影珍珠
I have to go all the way back and get a whole other ender pearl.
因为那个该死的捐赠规则，这又花了我一个小时
Because of the whole donation rule, that took another hour.
我已经砍了五个小时的木头了
I have been chopping logs for five hours.
好了，祷告时间到
All right, it's prayer time.
一、二、三……九、十
One, two, three, nine, ten.
好了，让我们干了这票
All right, let's do this thing.
记住，我们不能先动手
Remember, we can't kill him.
我们必须让末影龙先打第一下
We have to let the ender dragon get in the first hit.
好了，我们有大概六分四十秒来干掉这家伙
Okay, so we have like six minutes, 40 seconds to kill this thing.
否则我们就会输掉整个挑战
Or else we literally lose the challenge.
之前的一切都将付诸东流
All this will be for nothing.
好了，末影龙已经正式打到我们了
Okay, so the ender dragon has officially hit us.
哦，不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
好，我们不能从这场战斗中逃跑
Okay, so we can't run away from this fight.
天啊
Oh, gosh.
好了，我还剩下四分钟
Okay, I have four minutes left.
来吧
Come on.
老兄，我现在这弓箭射得简直出神入化
Dude, I'm going crazy with these bow shots right now.
我几乎箭无虚发
I'm like not missing.
就在我用弓箭招呼末影龙的时候，我回想起了那些我不得不捐出的钻石
As I was bowing down the ender dragon, I thought, of all the diamonds I had to donate,
回想起了那些我必须进行的祷告
of all the prayers I had to take,
回想起了那些我本不想招惹却又不得不面对的怪物
of all the mobs I didn't even want to fight, but I had to.
最重要的是，我想，当我的游戏角色迎来死亡的那一天
And most importantly, I thought, when the day comes for my Minecraft character to die,
他是否能与安拉同在
will he be with Allah?
在最后几秒钟，我给了末影龙最后一击
I landed the last hit on the ender dragon, with just a few seconds left to spare,
然后跳进了传送门
and hopped into the portal.
我成功了
I had done it.
我在没有违背任何伊斯兰教规的情况下，通关了《我的世界》
I beat Minecraft, without breaking any of the rules of Islam.
但紧接着，我看到了一些东西
But then I saw something.
等一下
Wait a second.
我们是谁？
Who are we?
“我们曾经被称作高山的精灵”
Once we were called the spirit of the mountain.
等等
Wait.
“而后是神明”
Then gods?
等等，这些东西是神
Wait, these things are gods?
但我不能在安拉之上有任何别的神明啊
But I can't have any other god over Allah.
那，等等，那岂不是说……这压根儿就没戏唱啊
That, wait, that means, that means it's impossible.
不！
No!